Nadeem Shah

Medical Engineer

As an AI enthusiast with an engineering background and 2 years of R&D experience in the medical device industry, my passion for transforming the healthcare system led me to pursue a specialization in 'AI in Image & Signal Processing' for my master's degree. I have competent skills in Python (1.0 grade in a university course) and relevant experience with MATLAB, complemented by completion of the Machine Learning course at my university and enrolment in the Andrew Ng ML Specialization on Coursera.



nadeemhusainshah@gmail.com

+4915753278448

Umfassungsstraße 55, 39124 Magdeburg, Germany

14 June, 1994

linkedin.com/in/EngrNadeemShah

in

EDUCATION

MSc Medical Systems Engineering Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg

German Grade: 1.8

Deepenings

 AI in Image and Signal Processing

Research Track -> Project (15 CP): Calculating posture from 2D pressure distributions using AI methods

Bachelor of Engineering in Biomedical Ziauddin University, Karachi

12/2015 - 12/2019

German Grade: 1,4

Achievements

 Got 4th position in the whole batch

 Received a merit-based scholarship of 40%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Biomedical Engineer

Tech4Life Enterprises, Karachi

08/2020 - 03/2022

Hardware and Innovation Dept.

It is an innovative research and design company, specialized in telemedicine and point-of-care devices

Major Duties

- Design, develop, test and modify hardware products
- Design & develop a software framework for hardware devices on Arduino in collaboration with the software team

Trainee Biomedical Engineer Jinnah Medical College Hospital, Karachi

01/2020 - 07/2020

Dept. of Biomedical Engineering

Solved several complaints by troubleshooting and repairing medical devices

MOOCS

Machine Learning Specialization (10/2022 - Present)

Computer Vision Basics (11/2020 - 12/2020)

Coursera

Al For Everyone (05/2020 - 06/2020)

Coursera

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python				0
MATLAB	•		0	0
C++	•	0	0	0
Arduino	•			0
AutoCAD Adobe Illustrator	•	0	0	0
Autodesk Eagle PCB Designing	•	0	0	0
Microsoft Office				

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Final Year Project

Designed a MyoGenu box and MyoGenu app that classifies healthy and unhealthy muscles of the knee using a machine learning algorithm

Line Follower Robot

Baby Incubator

Variable DC Power Supply

Automatic Water Level Detector & Water Pump Controller

PUBLICATIONS

Design and Development of Human Knee Joint Muscle(s) Classification System using Machine Learning

I am the first author of this research paper. It was accepted by the Pakistan Engineering Council and published in the first volume of their journal "Pakistan Journal of Engineering"